so just like loop unrolling which had
similar benefits
function call inlining has a similar
downside and that downside is the code
bloat suppose we have the original
program and it calls a function and then
it continues and calls the same function
from another place and so on let's say
that our function is 10 instructions and
then a return so now when we do our
inlining what we will do is we will
effectively put the 10 instructions here
and replace the call
and also take the same instructions put
them here and replace the call so what
used to be ten instructions plus one for
the return
plus two for calling
altogether 13 instructions now becomes
10 instructions here and 10 instructions
here and although we eliminated the
overheads and there are no longer
function calls and returns and possibly
some small amount of argument copying
and so on still we have replicated the
body of the function as many times as
there are places in the code that call
it some functions are called from
hundreds of places which means
that the body of the function will now
be replicated many many times
this means that we really need to be
judicious about
when do we do function call inlining we
cannot inline all of the functions that
we want
we want to inline functions that are
small because the fewer instructions we
have here
the more we are likely to offset the
additional instructions we put in here
by the removal of some of the overheads
but as the function goes big
the replication
results in a lot more code than the
original calling and returning code did